SOPHIA SKORDAS

(773) 218-7558 Cell

skordas7@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sophiaskordas/

Professional Summary

Over fourteen years of focus on customer service within the progressive experience in the IT industry, worked specifically on internal/external customer support, accuracy, pricing, cost modeling, and sales support. Throughout those years several promotions were earned which resulted in increased responsibility. Experienced collaborator on implementation projects, work-flow/process improvement, and user acceptance testing.

Professional Experience

Forsythe Technology, Inc. Skokie, Illinois

August 2011 to January 2015

Product Sales Support Analyst - Security

- ~ Quoted and configured complex technical solutions through Salesforce.com for
- ~ Highly specialized in Security & Network products (Ex. Checkpoint, RSA, McAfee, Blue Coat, and Juniper)
- ~ Managed manufacturer deal registrations to maximize deeper discounts
- ~ Responsible for Quote to Cash: Configuration to Proposal to Booking
- ~ Utilized Cost Analytic Tool to leverage opportunities for additional margin
- ~ Supported Account Managers, Solution Architects, Solution Specialists, and Clients

August 2009 to July 2011

Product Sales Support Analyst - Storage

- ~ Accountable for accurate technical EMC / Symantec / Data Domain / QLogic solutions for clients
- ~ Applied for manufacturer deal registrations to secure deeper discounts
- ~ Responsible for Quote to Cash: Configuration to Proposal to Booking
- ~ Sales Certified for EMC / NETAPP / Symantec / QLogic
- ~ Processed more than \$9,000K per year in margin for the combined 5 regions

May 2007 to July 2009

Client Advocate

- ~ Pre- and post-sales contact with clients to facilitate productive long-term relations
- ~ Performed inside sales duties, supporting Account Managers, Solution Architects, Solution Specialists and clients
- ~ Assisted with cross-selling activities, and developed opportunities for margin growth
- ~ Reviewed client contracts (ex. Statement of Work and Master Sale Agreements)
- ~ Resolved issues/problems through independent thinking
- ~ Supported 3 of the top 10 Account Managers

December 2003 to May 2007

Pricing Analyst -X86

- ~ Configured and priced IBM/HP X-Series/Proliant servers, desktops and laptop solutions
- ~ Accountable for accurate technical configurations & pricing solutions, including registrations discounts
- ~ Maintained accurate IBM Special Bid pricing and HP Big Deal pricing
- ~ Spoke directly to clients regarding their technical needs and possible solutions

EMC Corporation Chicago, Illinois

April 2000 to December 2003

Sr. District Sales Process Coordinator – Enterprise/Commercial

- ~ Acted as liaison between multi-million dollar clients and EMC Sales personnel
- ~ Processed \$12.3M in business transactions for region-covering 9 states/4 districts
- ~ Accountable for accurate revenue billing for each region
- ~ Maintained backlog reports to insure timely shipping & billing of outstanding orders
- ~ Managed accurate inventory control sales forecasts for upper level management
- ~ On-boarded new Account Managers/Technical Support
- ~ Coordinated and participated in team and client meetings as needed

OCE - USA, INC. Chicago, Illinois

January 1997 to March 2000

National Accounts Administrator

- ~ Support Sr. Vice President of National Accounts and 12 National Account Managers
- ~ Compiled and prepared all reporting for C-level management
- ~ Managed interaction with Area Sales Managers across USA and South America
- ~ Systematized and maintained accurate records for multiple orders throughout multiple sales regions
- ~ Controlled preparation of contract bids

January 1997 to August 1998

Area Sales Administrator - Engineering

- ~ Administered and processed all machine orders for the Chicago Sales Team
- ~ Provided accurate monthly billings to upper level management
- ~ Developed and created training of Order Booklet, Sales Reporting and Order Process for Sales Team
- ~ Provided central point of contact for all clients
- ~ Planned, ordered and organized Trade Shows

ABN-AMRO NORTH AMERICA, SERVICE CORP. Chicago, Illinois

May 1995 to January 1997

Team Leader Customer Service Call Center

- ~ Managed staff of 15 representatives and assist in cross-floor supervision of 75
- ~ Resolved issues related to customers' personal and business accounts
- ~ Completed special departmental training projects assigned by senior management
- ~ Conducted recruiting and training for new staff members

Education

LOYOLA UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO

Bachelor of Business Administration

Technical Summary

- **Skills:** SAP, Oracle versions through 12.1.2, Salesforce.com, Microsoft Office Suite 2013, Cisco AnyConnect Mobility Client (VPN), Lync 2013, WebEx
 - Certifications: Juniper Junos Software Advantage Certification, Juniper Vision Sales Certification, Juniper JNSA-NI Advanced Network JNSA-EX Certification, Juniper JNSA-NI Advanced Network JNSA-MMX Certification, Riverbed (CS) Cascade Specialization, Blue Coat Sales Foundation Accreditation Certification, Blue Coat Advanced Security Specialty Certification, Riverbed (RSAP) Sales Accreditation Certification, Check Point Sales Certification (CPSPC)